LUCY JONES CURRICULUM VITAE

📞 07919098611 🖾 lucyjpjones@gmail.com 🗣 1 Ribblesdale Road, London, SW16 6SF 🛅 www.linkedin.com/in/lucy-jones-1304

PROFILE

Challenge-driven economics graduate with over 5 years professional experience in merchandising and sales. A self-motivated and fast learner, seeking to combine strong analytical skills with exceptional communication skills to transition into the field of software development.

KEY SKILLS

Strong numerical and analytical skills

Building and maintaining relationships

Success in managing and developing others

Strong negotiation skills applied within both retail and sales environment

Commercial and customer awareness

Exceptional organisational skills with proven ability to manage workload to meet deadlines and hit targets

Highly proficient in spreadsheets showing meticulous attention to detail

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Full current clean driving license

Advanced excel skills, confident using pivot tables and Vlookups

Basic knowledge of Python 3 programming language

EDUCATION

Leeds Beckett University

2011-2014

First Class Honors degree in Economics for Business (BA)

West Kirby Grammar School

2004-2011

A Level: Product Design (A), Business and Economics (B), Mathematics (C)

AS Level: Geography (C)

10 GCSE's all A* to C, including: Mathematics, English and Science

WORK EXPERIENCE

Debenhams, Senior Assistant Planner (Electricals- Personal Care) November 2019- May 2020

- Managed my own department, Personal Care Electricals.
- Implemented department plans for forthcoming seasons through historical analysis and consideration of the business trading calendar and objectives.
- Proven success by over-achieving my sales plan last season by 104% and exceeding my target margin by 8%
- Lead the discussion around performance at supplier range reviews and liaised with the buyer to decide on the product range for the season.
- Reviewed and updated continuity line cards in order to action rebuys.
- Created adhoc reports to improve workflow efficiency and support the team in decision-making.
- Managed supplier funding to ensure we achieved our best product margins and took advantage of any marketing opportunities.
- Presented department figures in weekly trade meetings to divisional directors in the Merchandiser's absence.

Foxtons (Battersea), Lettings Negotiator

May 2019-November 2019

- Actively sourced and managed my own client database while continuously building and maintaining strong rapport with over 100 applicants.
- Handled incoming enquires from online, telephone and walk-ins, and provided support for front office with meet and greets and general administration.
- Used own initiative to conduct viewings tailored to the client's individual needs and followed up with feedback.
- Carried out rental inspections and took control of the entire referencing process and signing of contracts.
- Proven ability of meeting and exceeding personal targets by obtaining top performer recognition.

Debenhams, Established Assistant Planner (Gifts- Women's Gifts, Season and Gift Experiences)

September 2017- May 2019

- Managed my own departments and helped to deliver an annual sales revenue of over £25m.
- Monitored department performance and re-forecasted to ensure we were achieving our sales and profit targets, whilst highlighting any risks.

PERSONAL ACHIEVEMENTS & AWARDS

Achieved a <u>Diploma</u> of professional Interior Design through the British College of Interior Design

Successfully completed <u>'Python</u> <u>for Everybody'</u> through the University of Michigan on Coursera

Code Institute <u>'5 Day Coding</u> Challenge'

Completed <u>'Learn Ruby'</u> through CodeAcademy

Awarded long lettings negotiator <u>'Hero of the Month'</u> through Foxtons

Gold <u>Duke of Edinburgh Award</u>

Completed the <u>Liverpool half</u> marathon raising over £1,000 for 'Made With Hope' charity

Set up a <u>'virtual horse race day'</u> through zoom raising over £400 for Pancreatic cancer

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Skiing

Yoga

Running

Travelling

REFEREES

Available upon request

- Provided valuable coaching and training to allocators and new starters to help support their development.
- Supported the merchandiser with producing and maintaining planning sheets.
- Conducted detailed analysis to ensure appropriate product selection, quantities and phasing.
- Closely monitored in-season trading and identified opportunities for rebuys and markdown.
- Built strong relationships with suppliers in order to negotiate best payment terms, pricing and delivery times.
- Worked with finance to ensure any supplier payment queries were dealt with accordingly.
- Dealt with the set-up of recalls and product write-offs in stores.
- Department representative for improved and new stores, working closely with store planning to produce store plans and drive key decisions around product placement.
- Intake representative for home division attending regular meetings with logistics team.

House of Fraser- Assistant Merchandiser, Men's Accessories (Private Label) May 2017 - September 2017

- Assisted the merchandiser in monthly re-forecasting
- Analysed weekly reports and presented department figures to senior management in trade meetings.
- Created allocation plans and grade matrix for the season through analysis of store space and historical data.
- Managed a team of allocators to ensure an accurate and timely execution of intake and allocation.
- Reviewed and submitted markdown, completed promo-rolls and selected product for the promotional in-store events.
- Managed 'Best & Worst' to keep track of best/worst selling lines.
- Identified stock opportunities for transfers and recalls to help maximise sales potential.
- Attended store visits to develop commercial gain and maintain awareness of competition.
- Took ownership of running a competition between stores to help drive sales during an in-store event. As a result, sales averaged +15% vs. the previous year with the winning store taking an additional £70k on menswear.

House of Fraser- Allocator, Men's Accessories (Branded) January 2015 - May 2017

- Created allocation plans and managed intake in line with phasing.
- Managed stock and replenishment by reviewing and updating stock profiles and grade tables.
- Inputted and updated promotional activity on the system (Mercatus).
- Monitored sales across all stores and actioned transfers and recalls to maintain optimum stock levels.
- Managed line cards to effectively monitor potential sales and assist the merchandiser in completing the monthly forecast.
- Prepared reports for Monday trade and provided sales and stock information for supplier meetings.
- First point of contact for distribution centre, suppliers and stores.
- Managed and led the monthly allocator meetings and provided training for new allocators entering the business.
- Participated in the buddy scheme and adopted the role of super LIMA user.